>> Jem Young: 好的，所以我们的服务器已启动并正在运行。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: All right, so
our server is up and running.
我们把它映射到我们的过程我们把它映射到港口
We have it mapped to our process,
we have it mapped to the port,
它会重写所有东西
it rewrites everything.
所以现在让我们进行版本控制， cuz 版本控制意味着我可以
So now's let's do version control,
cuz version control means that I can
进行更改，我可以将其推送到 GitHub 或 Stash 或您喜欢的任何存储库。
make changes, I can push it the GitHub or
Stash or whatever repository you like.
你可以把它放下来在你的电脑上工作因为在这个时候
You can pull it down to work on your
computer because, at this point,
我们只是在一个节点环境里，服务器不再重要了。
we're just in a Node environment,
the server doesn't matter anymore.
版本控制，它仅记录对文件系统的更改以保留其历史记录。
Version control, it just records changes
to a file system to preserve its history.
有 Git ， Subversion， Mercurial，还有什么我忘了吗 ?
There's Git, Subversion, Mercurial,
is there anything else I'm forgetting?
>> Jem Young: 没有?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Nothing?
大家都知道 Git吗
Everybody just knows Git?
有趣的是 GitHub 不是 GitHub
Fun fact, what does GitHub or not GitHub,
我认为 Facebook 是使用 SVN， Subversion 还是 Mercurial?
I think Facebook uses SVN,
Subversion, or is it Mercurial?
Facebook 有一个 monorepo ，它们有一个存储库，用于
Facebook uses a monorepo,
they have one repository for
他们的密码都在 Facebook上
all of their code at Facebook.
因为 Git 不能像它们一样处理太多代码。
Because Git literally can't
handle as much code as they have.
对它有最大限度的限制
There's like a maximum limit on it.
我认为谷歌也有自己的定制存储库版本控制。
And I think Google has their own
custom repo version control as well.
奇怪的事实不适用于任何形式或时尚，但它只是知道的好。
Weird fact, does not apply in any form or
fashion, but it's just good to know.
这是我们最后的练习，我们将把我们的存储库推向一个 GitHub 存储库。
This is our final exercise, we're gonna
push our repository up to a GitHub repo.
但要做到这一点，我们需要采取一系列步骤。
But to do that,
we need to go through a series of steps.
因为希望 GitHub ，您已启用 SSH 密钥，而不是密码。
Because hopefully for GitHub, you have
your SSH keys enabled, not a password.
对于大多数人，您有 SSH 密钥。
And for most people, you have SSH keys.
如果在工作时使用 SSH ，那么可能强制您使用 SSH。
If you use it at work,
they probably force you to use SSH.
但我们要创建一个 Git 存储库，我们已经做了。
But we're gonna create a Git repository,
which we already did.
我们会创建一个 SSH 密钥，我们知道该怎么做。
We're gonna create an SSH key,
which we know how to do.
我们会将 SSH 密钥添加到授权密钥目录中
We're gonna add that SSH key to
the authorized keys directory,
我们已经做过了
which we've done.
我们会将 SSH 密钥添加到 GitHub。
We're gonna add the SSH key to GitHub.
我们要加上远程存储库然后我们就能把它全部推了
We're gonna add the the remote repo,
and then we're gonna push it all.
这比我们想象的要复杂得多
That was trickier than we thought it'd be.
我想那就更麻烦了
It was trickier I thought it'd be.
我以前也这么做过，这还真是太麻烦了。
And I've done this before, and
it's still like, what a hassle.
所以让我们现在就走吧，因为这是最后的一步。
So let's walk through it now,
because this is the final step.
一旦我们做了这个，我们能做的就是在本地机器上编码。
And once we do this, what we can do
is we can code on our local machines.
我们不需要登录服务器。
We don't need log in to a server.
这意味着我们可以使用我们的 IDE ，所有我们想做的工具，
So that means we can use our IDEs,
all the tools we wanna do,
我们可以在本地旋转节点服务器。
we can spin up the Node server locally.
然后我们就把这些都推到 GitHub 上
And then we can just push
that all to GitHub, and
当我们登录服务器时，可以将其下拉。
then when we log into the server,
we can pull it down.
然后重新启动服务器，然后进行所有更改。
And then restart our server and
then all the changes will be there.
一般来说，你不会在服务器上做任何开发。
And generally, you're not gonna do
any development on the server itself.
所以这其实是一个重要的步骤，但是
So this is actually a kind
of important step, but
让我们去看看怎么做
let's walk through on how to do it.
所以我做的第一件事就是创造了一个存储库。
So the first thing I did was
I created a git repository.
我做了这个
And I made this one.
现在可能是私事了，我一直都是在默认情况下使用的。
It's probably private right now,
cuz that's what I always use by default.
所以不要去那也不代表什么
So don't go there, it won't mean anything.
但我做的是，我去了我的主页。
But what I did was,
I went to my home page.
然后，我忘记了如何创建 Git 存储库。
And then, I forgot actually how
to create a Git repository.
我们走了我说了新存储库
Here we go, and I said New repository.
然后你把它叫做 " 公共或私人"
Then you call it something Public or
Private.
如果您没有 " 专用 " 选项，那么可能不为 GitHub Pro 付款。
If you don't have the Private option,
you probably don't pay for GitHub Pro.
没关系，你不需要，你可以让它公开。
That's okay, you don't need to,
you can make it public.
通常最好使用自述文件来初始化此存储库
It's usually best to initialize
this repo with a readme,
本结构简单，使用方便，易于实现。
it makes it easy to pull in.
如果您还没有节点，请添加 .gitignore 。
And add a .gitignore,
if you haven't already, for node.
所以它会忽略那些 node_modules ，所以
So it's gonna ignore those node_modules,
so
你不必每次都这么做
you don't have to commit those every time.
如果没有的话，我们会写一个，或者我给你演示如何快速写一个 .citignore 。
If not, we'll write one, or I'll show you
how to write a .gitignore really quick.
但是一般情况下，您不想推送您的 node_modules， cuz 可以
But generally, you don't wanna push
your node_modules, cuz they can be
数据的兆字节，兆字节和兆字节，当我们为我们建立 NPM 时。
megabytes and megabytes and megabytes of
data, when we have NPM to do that for us.
然后，如果需要，请添加许可证。
And then add a license if you want.
我已经做了一个 repo ，所以我不会再做另一个了。
And I already made a repo, so
I'm not gonna make another one.
大家都来了对吧
Everybody, we got this far, right?
好，下一步是创建 SSH 密钥。
Okay, next step was create an SSH key.
要做到这一点，我要切换到 cd ~ /.ssh/。
And to do that,
I'm gonna switch to cd ~/.ssh/.
然后用我们之前在其他电脑上用的那个命令
And then we're gonna use that command
we used earlier on our other computer,
但它仍在这儿工作 ssh - keygen
but it still works here, ssh-keygen.
我已经做了一个 SSH 密钥我不会再做一个了
And I've already made an ssh key,
I'm not gonna make another one.
但遵循的步骤是标准的。
But the steps follow is standard.
您只能使用 id_rsa，因为它是新的服务器
You can just use id_rsa,
because, it's a new server so
你在那里没有 SSH 密钥
you don't have any SSH keys on there.
除非你只是在为有趣的工作做 SSH 密钥而不去评判你
Unless you were just making SSH keys for
fun, not going to judge you.
因此，一旦我们添加了 SSH 密钥，我道歉，我犯了一个错误。
So once we add that SSH key,
I apologize, I made a mistake.
实际上，我们不需要将其添加到授权密钥中。
We actually don't need to add
it to the authorized keys.
仅当我们想在使用该服务器时添加 SSH 。
That's only if we wanna add
SSH in using that server.
所以我要把这条线取出来
So I'm gonna take this line out.
我很抱歉
I apologize.
这是一项正在进行中的工作。
It's a work in progress.
但是因为我们创建了 id_rsa，它是缺省密钥。
But because we created that id_rsa,
it's the default key.
当我们使用 GitHub 来 SSH 并推送文件或提取我们的文件时，
When we use GitHub to SSH and
push our files or pull our files,
它会自动查看此缺省值。
it's automatically going
to look at this default.
所以我们不需要做任何事情来把它添加到钥匙链上。
So we don't need to do anything to add it
to the key chain or anything like that.
大家都好到目前为止
Everybody, we're good so far.
没丢过人吗
Didn't lose anybody?
我们生成一个密钥。
We generate a key.
这里的情况有点棘手
It gets a little trickier here.
我们需要做的是将 SSH 密钥添加到 GitHub。
What we need to do is we need
to add the SSH key to GitHub.
如果我们点击这个链接
And if we click this link,
它会带您到 " 帮助 " 页面来说明如何执行该操作。
it'll take you to the Help page
explaining exactly how to do it.
但我们的方式是我可以走了
But the way we do it is, I can go,
只要点击一下我的个人档案图标
just click my profile icon on any spot,
转至 " 设置" ，转至 SSH ，我可以添加新的 SSH 密钥。
go to Settings, go to SSH,
and I can add a new SSH key.
就像上次我们做的那样我要说猫咪
And just like we did last time,
I'm gonna say cat id_rsa.
记住，它是公用密钥， .pub。
Remember, it's the public key, .pub.
>> Jem Young: 到目前为止还不错。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Good so far.
我们都得走了
We all got this far.
我们可以复制并粘贴。
And we can copy and paste that.
我们把它放在这里
And we put it in here.
我已经做过了
I've already done it.
我能再做一次但没问题
I can do it again, but
there's no point to it.
无论你想要什么我都给它一个完整的标题
I give it a title for whatever you want,
full stack front end.
删除我的密钥，假服务器密钥，不重要。
Delete me key, fake server key,
doesn't matter.
因此，添加 SSH 密钥。
So you add that SSH key in.
那你就有新的 SSH了
Then you'll have a new SSH.
因此，这允许我们连接到 GitHub ，而不是使用密码。
So this allows us to connect to GitHub,
instead of using a password.
你可能被挂在这部分了
Where you might have got
hung up on was this part.
这很微妙，你可能做到了，甚至都没意识到。
And it's subtle, and you've probably
done it and not even realized it.
我们需要在我们的服务器上添加远程到我们的新存储库。
We need to add the remote to
our new repo on our server.
但我们想用 SSH 的
But we wanna use the SSH one.
如果我们使用  它每次都要问我们一个用户名和密码。
If we use HTTPS, it's gonna ask us for
a username and password every single time.
那是个麻烦
That's a hassle.
再次，我们通常不希望使用密码，我们使用 SSH。
And again, we generally don't
wanna use passwords, we use SSH.
所有这些都发生在背景中。
So all this happens in the background.
现在，大多数人可能在一天中使用某种版本控制
Now, most of you probably work with
some sort of version control in your day
一天的工作
to day job.
你可能是在默认情况下成立的，你甚至都没意识到。
And you probably have this all set up by
default, and you didn't even realize it.
但就像我说的这个课在兜风里
But like I said,
this class is going under the hood and
看看到底发生了什么
seeing exactly what's going on.
所以使用 SSH。
So use SSH.
我们想把它复制过来
We wanna copy that over.
现在我要换了我还在我的服务器上
So now I'm gonna switch,
I'm still on my server.
我要切换回 var/www/app/
I'm gonna switch back to var/www/app/,
and I'm gonna say,
嗯，我有一个存储库， cuz 我可以做 git 状态。
hmm, I have a repository,
cuz I can do git status.
我知道我在存储库里
And I know I'm in a repository.
所以我 wanna 做的是远程添加原点，我认为这是正确的。
So what I wannna do is git remote
add origin, I think that's correct.
我要检查码头的情况
I'm gonna check the docs just in case.
Git 远程添加源，是。
Git remote add origin, yeah.
我在 GitHub 中抽取的 Git 配置文件中
And I paste in the git config file
that I pulled from GitHub for
我刚创建的新回购协议
my new repo I just created.
>> Jem Young: 有道理吗 ? 到目前为止都和我一起吗
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Makes sense?
Everybody with me so far?
有一件事，我已经做过了，所以我必须确保我的指示有效。
One thing, I already did this, so
I had to make sure my instructions worked.
你要做的一件事就是把遥控器
One thing you're gonna run into
is you're gonna add the remote,
你可以说 git remote -v.
you can say git remote -v.
只是为了验证你是否正确，你可能做到了。
Just to verify that you had it correctly,
you probably did.
好的一件事就是我们要做点什么
Cool, one thing is we're
gonna do git commit.
如果你做了 git 承诺，就会像你需要配置的那样
And if you do git commit, it's gonna throw
something in, like you need to configure
您的用户名，全局用户名和全局名。
your username, your global username,
and your global name.
当你把它放在 GitHub上的时候
That's just so when you push,
when it lands on GitHub,
一定会有人归咎的
there'll be someone attributed to it.
不是随便的人
Not some random person.
你不用把真实的电邮放进你的真名里
You don't have to put in your real email,
you don't have to put in your real name,
无论你是谁
be whoever you wanna be.
但这只是
But it's just so
等你在推的时候你就知道那个推力是从哪里来的
later when you're pushing, you know
exactly where that push came from.
所以说 git 配置更好
So sometimes it's better
to say git config.
Jem 破折号我的服务器不管在哪里都不重要
Jem dash, my own server,
wherever, doesn't matter.
它只告诉你它是从哪里来的，而不是你的家用计算机。
It just tells you where it came from,
rather than your home computer.
所以现在我要加一个 gigtignore 文件以防你没有
So right now I'm gona add a .gitignore
file just in case you didn't.
所以我可以说 vi .
So I can say vi .gitignore.
> > Jem Young: 这里已经有一个了。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And
there's already one in here.
这是在我创建此存储库时自动创建的。
That was created automatically
when I created this repo.
但是如果你的 tignore 是空白的，不用担心，
But if your gitignore is blank,
no worries,
您就可以说 node_modules/。
you can just say node_modules/.
怎么了
Yes?
>> 演讲者 2: [COUGH] 但是如果您已经进行了落实，如果已推送
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [COUGH] But if you've
already commited, if you've already pushed
你还没到位呢难道你不想先把那些都炸掉吗
and you didn't have that in place,
don't you wanna blow those away first?
在将其添加到您的 git 落实或 .gitignore 之前 ?
Before adding it to your git commit,
or .gitignore?
这样，您就无法 - >> Jem Young : 你会被困住。
Cuz otherwise you won't be able to-
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: You'll be stuck.
>> 扬声器 2: 将永远被忽略。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: It'll be ignored forever.
>> Jem Young: 您可以手动打开 GitHub 并删除该文件，但是
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: You could manually go
on GitHub and delete that file, but
这不太合适
that's not preferrable.
因此，您想做的是在进行此忽略之前，您可以对其进行注释。
So what you wanna do is before you make
this ignore, you can comment it out.
这就是给那些已经和
So this is for
people who have already committed and
他们把他们的 node_modules 推到 GitHub ，很好。
they pushed their node_modules
up to GitHub, which is fine.
但我们想立即删除这些 node_modules ，然后落实。
But what we wanna do is wanna delete
those node_modules for now, then commit.
该落实将转至 GitHub，它将除去 node_modules ，并且
And that commit will go up to GitHub,
it'll remove the node_modules, and
然后我们再评论
then we'll comment this back in.
如果是在杰姆的错的话那一天就结束了
And if this falls under Jem's bad,
it's the end of the day.
我应该将此添加到使用 .gitgnore的指示信息中。
I should have added this to
the instructions to use a .gitgnore.
但如果你没有，你可以现在就去补充。
But just in case you haven't,
you can go and add it now.
而且 .gitignore 非常好，因为它忽略了日志文件，
And .gitignore is great because,
well, it ignores log files,
所有的点文件你不需要做的事情
all the dot files,
things you don't actually need to commit.
但如果你没那么做那就是我要做的事
But just in case you haven't,
that's what .gitignore does.
但我现在就要写辞职了
But I'm gonna write quit right now.
我修改了吉蒂诺
And I'll modify the .gitignore.
所以我要承诺
So I'm gonna commit.
所以我可以说 " git commit -am " ，只是添加正在跟踪的所有内容，
So I can say git commit -am, is just
adding everything that's being tracked,
这一切都被修改过了
and it's just anything
that's been modified.
git commit Modify git 忽略。
git commit Modify git ignore.
>> Jem Young: 然后我可以推。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And then I can push.
所以我可以说 git 推来推去的主人
So I can say git push origin master.
如果运行该落实命令，并且它表示您需要配置您的用户名
If you ran that commit command and it's
saying you need to configure your username
和密码现在就去做
and password,
just go ahead and do that now.
你只需要做一次
You only have to do it one time.
> > Jem Young: 然后我们就被推高了。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And, we just pushed up.
>> Jem Young: 有人卡在任何地方吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Did anybody
get stuck on any part?
我要回去了
I will go back over it.
Git 可以是棘手的。
Git can be tricky.
>> 扬声器 2: 我刚刚创建了 .gitignore。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I just
created the .gitignore.
但我已经说过了，因为我还得炸掉我的东西。
But I commented out because I
still have to blow away, my stuff.
>> Jem Young: 是。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yes.
你还记得怎么删除吗
Do you remember how to delete something?
>> 扬声器 2: 那么，它是 rm。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Well, it's rm.
>> Jem Young: 是的，但因为我们要删除所有内容，我们使用递归。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yes, but because we wannna
delete everything, we use the recursive.
所以我们说， rm -rf.
So we say, rm -rf.
这很危险 [LAUGH]。
Which is very dangerous [LAUGH].
再一次，你去除了档案，没有垃圾桶，它就不见了。
Again, you're removing files,
there's no trash can, it's just gone.
但是如果您意外地落实了 node_modules，
But if you accidentally
committed your node_modules,
在 .gitignore 中忽略该行，然后删除您的 node_modules。
ignore that line in .gitignore,
and then delete your node_modules.
请落实该操作，然后将其向上推送。
Commit that, and then push it up.
在 Git [LAUGH] 的整个过程中教导了一个比我更聪明的人。
There is an entire course on Git [LAUGH]
taught someone much smarter than me.
我们会把它联系起来
We will link that out.
你的 Git 会变得一团糟
Cuz Git will get really messy.
但我们现在没事了
But we're okay for now.
好吧，你按原主的方式，这个推应该已经转到了 GitHub了。
Okay, so you push origin master, the push
should have went through to GitHub.
所以当我们回到 GitHub 的时候
So when we go back to GitHub to that repo.
>> Jem Young: 我们看到了这些东西，现在他们可以给我了。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: We see I committed these
things and now they're available for me.
>> Jem Young: 所有人都走了吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Did everybody get this far?
我知道我们在征税我们已经从 Nginx 配置到 Git 调整
I know we're taxing, we have moved from
Nginx configuration to Git tweaking.
但现在我已经放弃了我要再克隆这个
But now that I've pulled up,
I'm gonna clone this repo again.
在我的本地机器上我要搬去
And on my local machine,
I'm gonna move into,
我想我有个项目文件夹
I think I have a projects folder.
我确实有一个项目文件夹。
I do have a projects folder.
有一个叫 Full-Stack-For-Fron趋向吗 ?
Is there one called
Full-Stack-For-Frontend?
我知道
I do.
我已经复制过了但我要移除它
I've already cloned that,
but I'm gonna remove that.
>> Jem Young: 因此，在任何类型的工作文件夹中，都有任何类型的 UI 文件夹，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: So in any sort of working
folder you have, any sort of UI folder,
执行 git 克隆。
do git clone.
我们准备好了我不知道为什么没有拷贝
And we're just gonna, oops,
I don't know why that didn't copy.
>> Jem Young: 我要克隆这个
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And I'm going to clone this.
然后再进行克隆，再贴在其中。
And git clone, paste that in.
我没删除吗
Did I not delete that?
我没有。
I did not.
>> Jem Young: Cool。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Cool.
> > Jem Young: 现在，我们要克隆它，实时地进行克隆。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Now, we're gonna
clone it in, for real this time.
我们正在做的就是我们正在做我们刚刚做的事情。
And all we're doing is we're
pulling down what we just did.
如果我想进 fsfev2
And if I wanna go into fsfev2.
现在我可以在 VS .
And now I can open that up in VS Code.
>> Jem Young: 现在我的应用程序在一个更容易的环境中使用，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And now I have my
app in a much easier environment,
那就更容易修改了
that's easier to modify.
现在，我可以随时修改此应用，例如添加分号。
And now I can modify this app at will,
like add semicolons.
我不知道为什么因为我喜欢分号
I don't know why,
because I like semicolons.
我可以为所欲为
I can do whatever I want.
我可以把它推上去，然后在我的服务器上，我就能把它拉上，
I can commit this, push it up, and then
on my server, I can just git pull, and
把它拉出来重新装我的服务器
pull that in, reload my server.
现在我修改了我的应用程序，我可以和一群人分享。
And now I've modified my app fresh, and I
can share this out with a bunch of people.
现在， 10 个人可以在我的应用程序上工作，然后针对服务器运行。
So ten people can work on my app now and
then run against the server.
如果我们想，我也不知道，如果我们明天再这样做的话。
If we wanted to, I don't know,
if we'll do that even tomorrow.
但如果你想
But if you wanted to,
我们可以设置一个自动执行最新更改的 cron 作业。
we can set up a cron job that
automatically pulls in the latest changes.
我不推荐这么做
I don't recommend doing that.
如果有人做了些奇怪的事，那就可以把你自己变成一个角落
That's a surefire way to get yourself into
a corner if someone does something weird
然后将服务器的 cuz 配置为不正确。
and then takes down the server cuz
they configured something incorrectly.
但是对于您自己的开发服务器，这是一种很好的做法。
But for your own development server,
it's a good way of doing things.
这就是我 jemyoung.com 的方式，它是这样配置的。
That's how I do my jemyoung.com,
it's configured like that.
所以我在本地开发一个 Python 服务器，我把它推上去，
So I do development locally on
a Python server, I push it up, and
它一旦准备好就自动拉入
it automatically pulls it
in once it's ready to go.